Guide to the Virginia Barber Literary Agency Records, 1975-2003 RL.01329
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Virginia Barber Literary Agency records
1975-2003
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Virginia Barber Literary Agency
RL.01329
52.5 Linear Feet
.0002 Gigabytes
Virginia Barber became a literary agent in 1971 and opened her own agency in 1974. The Virginia Barber Literary Agency was sold to the William Morris Agency in 2001. Among the authors she represented have been Rosellen Brown, Andrew Delbanco, James Dodson, Sue Monk Kidd, Peter Mayle, Alice Munro, David Nasaw, Anita Shreve, and Anne Rivers Siddons. She has served on the Board and as President of Women's Media Group and on the Boards of Literacy Partners, Duke University Libraries, and Poets and Writers. The collection includes client files and correspondence for the VBLA's many clients during the late 1970s through the early 2000s. There are also legal and financial materials, correspondence files with other agencies and publishers, including Virago Books, and materials from Barber's work with professional organizations such as the Independent Literary Agents Association. Notable clients represented in this collection include Peter Mayle, Anita Shreve, MacDonald Harris, and Paul Ehrlich.
40,000 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is restricted: Access to legal and financial files (such as contracts and royalty statements) will require written permission from the client, for the life of the client.
Provenance
The Virginia Barber Literary Agency Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2013.
Historical Note
Virginia Barber became a literary agent in 1971 and opened her own agency in 1974. The Virginia Barber Literary Agency was sold to the William Morris Agency in 2001. Among the authors she represented have been Rosellen Brown, Andrew Delbanco, James Dodson, Sue Monk Kidd, Peter Mayle, Alice Munro, David Nasaw, Anita Shreve, and Anne Rivers Siddons. She has served on the Board and as President of Women's Media Group and on the Boards of Literacy Partners, Duke University Libraries, and Poets and Writers.
Collection Overview
The collection includes client files and correspondence for the VBLA's many clients during the late 1970s through the early 2000s. There are also legal and financial materials, correspondence files with other agencies and publishers, including Virago Books, and materials from Barber's work with professional organizations such as the Independent Literary Agents Association. Notable clients represented in this collection include Peter Mayle, Anita Shreve, MacDonald Harris, and Paul Ehrlich.
Separated Material
The agency's files related to Alice Munro were sent to the University of Calgary Special Collections to accompany their Alice Munro Collection.
Related Material
Additional materials on client Anita Shreve can be found in the Anita Shreve Papers, also held at the Rubenstein Library.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Literary agents -- United States -- Correspondence; Authors -- Correspondence; Publishers and publishing; Machine-readable artifacts; Virginia Barber Literary Agency; Virago Press; Barber, Virginia; Shreve, Anita; Ehrlich, Paul R.; Harris, MacDonald, 1921-1993; Dodson, James; Siddons, Anne Rivers; Brown, Rossellen; Mayle, Peter; Barber, Virginia
- Client Correspondence, 1978-2003, 20 boxes
  Scope and Contents note
  The Client Correspondence series contains files kept by the Virginia Barber Literary Agency on each of its clients, and occasional potential clients or non-clients, while they were active with the agency between 1978 and the sale of VBLA in 2001. Some files extend to 2003 and overlap the VBLA's acquisition by the William Morris Agency.
  Most files include correspondence between Barber and her staff, the client, and various publishers and editors who reviewed the client's work and considered publication. Some files include drafts or proposals shared by the client. Occasionally, files include clippings, press coverage, or publicity materials created by the publisher for particular books or publications. All offical legal and financial documents have been removed from this series to the Legal and Financial Materials series, which has some access restrictions. A small selection of files from non-clients and editors is included at the end of this series.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Collection contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
  - Abbott, Dorothy, 1985-1986, 1988-1990, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Abelson, Edward, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Ackerman, Diane, 2000-2003, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Adams, Gail Galloway, 1986, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Acocella, Marisa, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Allitt, Patrick, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Allison, Eric and Mary Ann, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
  - Allport, Susan, 1986-2003, 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Douglas, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Rex, 1984-1987, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Armstrong, Jon, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Ascher, Barbara, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Attanasio, A. A., 1984-1995, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Aujderheide, Pat, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Bacon, Charlotte, 2001-2003 (Box 1)
  - Bagdasarian, Adan, 2001-2002 (Box 1)
  - Bailey, Hilary, 1985, 1988-1990 (Box 1)
  - Barker, Pat, 1983-1996, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Barrett, Judith, 1985-1987 (Box 1)
  - Barscocchini, Peter, 1979-2002, 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Benderly, Beryl, 1983-1990, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Bengis, Ingrid, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Beranbaum, Rose, 1984-1989, 1996 (Box 2)
  - Berger, John J., 1994-1998, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Bills, Greg, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Bingham, Rob, 1993-1997 (Box 2)
  - Blackburn, Julia, 1990-1991 (Box 2)
  - Blakeslee, Sandra, 1986-1998, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Blackford, Charles, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Boas, Jacob, 1993-1995 (Box 2)
  - Bodo, Peter, 1985 (Box 2)
  - Brady, Kathleen, 1992-1995 (Box 2)
  - Braestrup, Kate, 1988-1989 (Box 2)
  - Brandon, Jay, 1984-1997, 9 folders (Box 2)
  - Breasted, Mary, 1986-1991 (Box 2)
  - Bregman, Alice, 1984-1988, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Brenner, Leslie, 1990-1994, 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Brookfield, William, 1986-1990 (Box 3)
  - Brown, Alan, 1983-1994, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Brown, Michael, 1980-1987, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Brown, Rosellen, 1980-2001, 7 folders (Box 3)
  - Broyard, Sandy, 1997 (Box 3)
  - Brummels, J. V., 1986 (Box 3)
  - Burke, Martyn, 1988-1997, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Burnett, Allison, 2001-2002 (Box 3)
  - Byham, William, 1990-1998, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Byrd, Max, 1983-1995, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - Byrd, Max, 1996-2003, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Carter, Robert, 1988-1990 (Box 4)
  - Carynnyck, Marco, 1975-1979 (Box 4)
  - Casten, George, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Cates, David, 2001-2002 (Box 4)
  - Cather, Willa, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Chabon, Michael, 1990-1994 (Box 4)
  - Chace, Rebecca, 1998 (Box 4)
  - Chagall, David, 1985 (Box 4)
  - Chamberlain, Diane, 1993-2003, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Chase, Deborah, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Cheetham, Mic, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Chertow, Marian, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Clancy, John, 1980-1988 (Box 4)
  - Clay, Grady, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
  - Clynes, Manfred, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Cochrane, Mick, 1996-1998, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Cohen, Judith Beth, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Cohn, Rachel, 2002-2003 (Box 4)
  - Cole, K. C., 1989-2003, 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Collins, Carol, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Collins, Tony, 1989-1990 (Box 4)
  - Conrad, Brad, 1984-1985 (Box 4)
  - Cooley, Mayilyn, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Coram, Robert, 1997-1999, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Coyle, Beverly, 1988-2003, 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Craig, Peter, 1993 (Box 5)
  - Cravens, Gwyneth, 1980-1991, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Cummins, Ann, 1993-1996 (Box 5)
  - Custen, George, 1993-2003 (Box 5)
  - D'Ambrosio, Charlie, 1993-1994 (Box 5)
  - Daniel, Mark, 1988-1993, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Daniels, Kate, 1983-1989 (Box 5)
  - Danziger, Danny, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Davis, Hope Hale, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
  - Daugharty, Jarica, 1996-2001 (Box 5)
  - DeChristofero, Ron, 1979-1980 (Box 5)
  - DeGeneres, Betty, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Delbanco, Andrew, 1993-2002, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Dew, Robb Forman, 1986-1992, 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Dodson, James, 1981-2003, 7 folders; 1 CD-RW, 1.61 MB (Box 5, Digital-materials RL01329-SET-0001, Box Digital Media Box 1)
    Scope and Contents
    CD-RW contains 14 files in DOC format. The files are a draft of Dodson's book, "Ben Hogan: An American Life."
  - Dooley, Susan, 1980-1991, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Doty, Carolyn, 1986-1995, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Druett, Joan, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Drummond, Emma, 1990 (Box 6)
  - Egan, Jennifer, 1990-1995, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Ehrlich, Paul and Anne, 1980-2003, 12 folders (Box 6)
  - Eichler, Glenn, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Eichler, Mim, 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Ellis, Charles, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - Ellison, Emily, 1989-1992 (Box 6)
  - Emery, Thomas, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Engel, Charlotte, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Engel, Marian, 1981-1988, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Fairbairns, Zoe, 1982-1990, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Farhi, Moris, 1988-1989 (Box 6)
  - Ferrigno, Robert, 1993-1994 (Box 6)
  - Findley, Timothy, 1990-1993, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Findley, Timothy, 1993-1995, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Fitch, Stona, 1990-1993 (Box 7)
  - Flad, Barbel, 1989 (Box 7)
  - Frush, Jim, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Flaste, Richard, 1983-1988 (Box 7)
  - Forche, Carolyn, 1981-2003, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Forward, Susan, 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Frank, Katherine, 1990-1994, 2001-2003, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Freeman, David, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Friedman, Mickey, 1991-1994, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Gadd, Laurence, 1985 (Box 7)
  - Gadol, Peter, 1988-1989 (Box 7)
  - Galinsky, Ellen, 1980-2003, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Gallman, Kuki, 1990-1992 (Box 7)
  - Gandal, Keith, 1990-1994 (Box 7)
  - Garner, Helen, 1980-1993, 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Gaston, Paul, 2001 (Box 7)
  - Gaussen, Sylvia, 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - Geary, Patricia, 1984-1992, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Gee, Sue, 1985, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Gentry, Lynwood, 1987-1988 (Box 8)
  - Geyer, Nancy, 1984-1986 (Box 8)
  - Gillespie, Joanne, 1989 (Box 8)
  - Gillespie, Larrian, 1984-1990, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Gingher, Marianne, 1980-1993, 5 folders (Box 8)
  - Goldberg, Rita, 1989 (Box 8)
  - Goodwin, Michael, 1978-1989, 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Gould, Jodie, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Grant, Linda, 1992-1994 (Box 8)
  - Gregoria, Vahe, 2001 (Box 8)
  - Gustaitis, Rasa, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Guy, David, 1980-1994, 5 folders (Box 8)
  - Haas, Barbara, 1985-1986 (Box 8)
  - Hall, June, 1981-1982 (Box 8)
  - Hall, Oakley, 2000-2003, 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Hammond, Diane, 1986, 1992 (Box 8)
  - Hardie, Sean, 1989-1993 (Box 8)
  - Harrington, Mary, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Harris, Diane, 1983-1989 (Box 8)
  - Harris, MacDonald, 1980-1993, 12 folders (Box 9)
  - Harvor, Beth, 1984-1985 (Box 9)
  - Havazelet, Ehud, 2000-2002 (Box 9)
  - Haviland, David, 1982-1983, 1989 (Box 9)
  - Hawke, Ethan, 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - Hayes, Elliott, 1984-1985 (Box 9)
  - Hayes, John, 1985 (Box 9)
  - Hazard, Edith, 1992-1994 (Box 9)
  - Hechinger, Grace, 1991 (Box 9)
  - Henderson, Bill, 1984-1991, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - van Herk, Aritha, 1980-1995, 5 folders (Box 9)
  - von Herzen, Lane, 1990-1994, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Heyn, Dalma, 1990-1995, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Hill, Rebecca, 1981-1989, 2 folders (Box 10)
  - von Hoffman, Nicholas, 1980-1993, 8 folders (Box 10)
  - Hogrefe, Jeffrey, 1982-1986 (Box 10)
  - Holton, Felicia, 1985-1986 (Box 10)
  - Homans, John, 1988 (Box 10)
  - Hoover, Thomas, 1980-1992, 7 folders (Box 10)
  - Horwitt, Sanford, 1992 (Box 10)
  - House, Adrian, 1989-1992 (Box 10)
  - Huddle, David, 1993-1995 (Box 10)
  - Hummer, Terry, 1990-1993 (Box 10)
  - Hune, Marsha, 1992-1995, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Humphries, Jenny Stone, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Imperato, Pascal (Pat), 1980-1987 (Box 11)
  - Janus, Sam, 1980 (Box 11)
  - Jiles, Paulette, 1993-1995 (Box 11)
  - Jolliffe, Gary, 1986, 1989 (Box 11)
  - de Jonge, Alex, 1989-1993, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Joseph, Jim, 2001 (Box 11)
  - Juska, Jane, 2002-2003, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Kafka, Kimberly, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Kagan, Elaine, 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Kalpakian, Laura, 1984-1987, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Kamen, Robert, 1981 (Box 11)
  - Kaufman, Pamela, 1994-1995 (Box 11)
  - Kaufman, Wallace, 1980, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Kavaler, Rebecca, 1985 (Box 11)
  - Kidd, Lucy Armstrong, 1988-1995, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Kidd, Sue Monk, 2001-2003, 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Kiernan, Fran, 1990-1994, 2001-2003 (Box 11)
  - Kittredge, Bill, and Steven Krauzer, 1980-1981 (Box 11)
  - Kittredge, William, 1982-1984 (Box 11)
  - Komamicki, Todd, 1993-1995, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Knowlton, Winthrop, 1990-1991 (Box 11)
  - Kogel, Joe, 1989 (Box 11)
  - Korn, Peter, 1993-1995 (Box 11)
  - Krauzer, Steven, 1983-1996, 7 folders (Box 12)
  - Krizan, Karen, 1990-1991 (Box 12)
  - Kurland, Helene, 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Laiken, Diedre, 1993 (Box 12)
  - Landau, David, 1989-1991 (Box 12)
  - Landers, Jonathon, 1987-1989 (Box 12)
  - La Puma, Salvatore, 1989-1991 (Box 12)
  - Larmore, Phoebe, 1980-1989 (Box 12)
  - Larsen, Karen, 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Lauber, Lynn, 1991-1992 (Box 12)
  - Law-Yone, Wendy, 1995 (Box 12)
  - Lee, Susan, 1984-1995, 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Leebron, Fred, 1995 (Box 12)
  - Leimbach, Marti, 1989-1996, 5 folders (Box 12)
  - Lentricchia, Melissa, 1989-1991 (Box 12)
  - Levant, Ron, 1987-1992 (Box 12)
  - Levine, Ann, 1987-1992 (Box 12)
  - Levine, Faye, 1987-1989 (Box 12)
  - Levine, Jo Ann, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Lieber, James, 1980-1995, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Lingeman, Richard, 1992-1995, 2001-2003, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Lipman, Elinor, 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Lipman-Bluman, Jean, 1986-1989 (Box 13)
  - Lipsky, David, 1990-1995 (Box 13)
  - Lipsyte, Robert, 2001-2003, 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Lone, Pat, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Louie, Elaine, 1980-1989, 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Lucas, Russell, 1989-1990 (Box 13)
  - Luceino, James, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Lynch, Jack, 1985-1987 (Box 13)
  - Lynch, Sarah-Kate, 2001-2003 (Box 13)
  - MacCracken, Mary, 1989 (Box 13)
  - Mackenzie, Norman, 1985-1987 (Box 13)
  - Maguire, John, 2001-2002 (Box 13)
  - Mallon, Thomas, 1986 (Box 13)
  - Markson, Elaine, 1980-1984 (Box 13)
  - Marston, Stephanie, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
  - Mason, Anita, 1991-1992 (Box 13)
  - Mattlin, Everett, 1993-1994 (Box 13)
  - May, Lary and Elaine, 1980 (Box 13)
  - Mayle, Peter, 1980-1985, 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Mayle, Peter, 1985-2003, 16 folders (Box 14)
  - Mayle, Simon, 1992-1994 (Box 14)
  - McCauley, Gerry, 1984 (Box 14)
  - McMillan, Robin, 1995 (Box 14)
  - McWatt, Tessa, 2003 (Box 14)
  - Messecar, Carol Ann, 1994-1996 (Box 14)
  - Meyerowitz, Steven, 1986 (Box 14)
  - Mickle, Sherry, 1989-1993 (Box 14)
  - Mickle, Shelley Fraser, 1993-1995 (Box 14)
  - Miller, Casey, and Kate Swift, 1978-1992, 5 folders (Box 15)
  - Miller, Cheryl, 1995 (Box 15)
  - Miller, Douglas and Marion Nowak,1979-1980 (Box 15)
  - Miller, Theresa, 1980-1987, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Mitchell, David and Cathy, 1980-1984 (Box 15)
  - Mitchell, Greg, 1985 (Box 15)
  - Mitchell, Reid, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Noel, Chris, 1986 (Box 15)
  - Monaco, James, 1980-1994, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Motz, Julie, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Murray, Yxta Maya, 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Myers, Norman, 1982-1994, 2002, 6 folders (Box 15)
  - Nasaw, David, 1991, 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Nashord, James, 2002-2003 (Box 15)
  - Neely, Jessica, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Neville, Suran, 1988-1989 (Box 15)
  - Nodal, Maxine, 1987 (Box 15)
  - Norwood, Christopher, 1980-1986, 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Nowak, Marion, 1979 (Box 15)
  - Ornstein, Robert, 1982-1991, 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Owen, Ursula, 1983-1985 (Box 15)
  - Parrish, Tim, 1995-1997 (Box 15)
  - Perrin, Ursula, 1980, 1985 (Box 15)
  - Pexa, Efriede, 1979-1982 (Box 15)
  - Pulger, John, 1990 (Box 15)
  - Pinfold, Wallace, 1992 (Box 15)
  - Pizzey, Erin, 1987 (Box 16)
  - Pope, Lois, 1989 (Box 16)
  - Powers, Richard Gid, 1989-2002 (Box 16)
  - Powledge, Fred, 1985 (Box 16)
  - Prados, John, 1985-1987 (Box 16)
  - Rajkovia, Rosa, 1985 (Box 16)
  - Redd, Joanne, 1985-1988 (Box 16)
  - Reit, Seymour, 1980-1994, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Rhett, Kathryn, 1995 (Box 16)
  - Robertson, Mary Elsie, 1981-1994, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Robson, Lucia St. Clair, 1984-2003, 5 folders (Box 16)
  - Rose, Frank, 1980-1989, 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Rosenberg, John, 1980-1988 (Box 16)
  - Russel, Frank, 1980-1987, 2 folders (Box 16)
  - Salaman, Nicholas, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Sanders, Marlene, 1987 (Box 17)
  - Scarr, Sandra, 1987-1992, 3 folders (Box 17)
  - Schaeffer, Neil, 1990-1992 (Box 17)
  - Schaeffer, Susan, 1986-1994, 5 folders (Box 17)
  - Schell, Jessie, 1980-1986 (Box 17)
  - Schlaks, Max, 2001-2001 (Box 17)
  - Schultz, Vicki, 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Schwartz, Lynne Sharon, 1979-1993, 5 folders (Box 17)
  - Schwenkmeyer, Barry, and Carmen Lynch, 1979-1990 (Box 17)
  - Scott, Jeremy, 1986-1987 (Box 17)
  - Scovall, Jane, 1984-1987 (Box 17)
  - Seidel, Phyllis, 1980 (Box 17)
  - Settle, Mary Lee, 1990-1994, 2 folders (Box 17)
  - Shafner, Ron, 1986 (Box 17)
  - Shapiro, Erin, 1983-1985 (Box 17)
  - Shapiro, Miles, 1990 (Box 17)
  - Shields, Carol, 1980-1983 (Box 17)
  - Shreve, Anita, 1985-1992, 2001-2003, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Siddons, Anne Rives, 1986-1994, 2001-2003, 9 folders (Box 18)
  - Siddons, Heyward, 1987 (Box 18)
  - Skaggs, Calvin and Merrill, 1980-1995, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Sloane, Arthur, 1989 (Box 18)
  - Sloman, Evelyne, 1984-1986 (Box 18)
  - Smith, Dinitia, 1984-1995, 3 folders (Box 18)
  - Smith, Patrick, 1991-1992 (Box 18)
  - Smith, Timothy, 1992 (Box 18)
  - Spark, Deborah, 1991-1992 (Box 19)
  - Sparkman, Brandon, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Spencer, Elizabeth, 1984-1994, 5 folders (Box 19)
  - Stallings, Penny, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
  - Sperling, Susan, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Steinberg, Laurence, 1986-1992, 2001-2003, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Stenton, William, 1994 (Box 19)
  - Stewart, Susan, 1986 (Box 19)
  - Stoddard, A., 1993 (Box 19)
  - Stone, Elizabeth, 1983 (Box 19)
  - Stranahan, Susan, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Strasser, Susan, 1984-1988 (Box 19)
  - Summer, Bob, 1986 (Box 19)
  - Swan, Mary, 2001-2003 (Box 19)
  - Szykitka, Walter, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Tennant, Emma, 1988 (Box 19)
  - Throckmorton, Peter, 1980-1990 (Box 19)
  - Tine, Robert, 1980-1986 (Box 19)
  - Tippins, Elizabeth, 1992-1995 (Box 19)
  - Tobar, Hektor, 1995 (Box 19)
  - Toledano, Rouhlac, 1987-1990 (Box 19)
  - Tournier, Jacques, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Trecker, Janice, 1985 (Box 19)
  - Tseo, George, 1993-1994 (Box 19)
  - Tyler, Sandra, 1992 (Box 19)
  - Vargas, Alberto, 1978-1984 (Box 19)
  - Verghese, Abraham, 1992 (Box 19)
  - Voss, Tom, 1979-1986 (Box 19)
  - Wales, Michael, 1981-1985 (Box 19)
  - Waller, Leslie, 1988-1989, 2 folders (Box 19)
  - Walsh, Lynn, 1987 (Box 19)
  - Walsh, Patricia, 1984-1985 (Box 19)
  - Ware, Ciji, 1994-1995 (Box 19)
  - Wasserman Miller, Norma, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Wedeman, Sara, 1986 (Box 19)
  - Weirather, Larry, 1985 (Box 19)
  - White, Antonia, 1977-1981 (Box 19)
  - White, Susan, 2001-2003 (Box 19)
  - Wiebe, Ruth, 1990 (Box 19)
  - Wier, Allen, 1989 (Box 19)
  - Wilford, John Noble, 1988-1991 (Box 19)
  - Willey, Margaret, 1986-1988 (Box 20)
  - Wisniewski, Mark, 1991-1994 (Box 20)
  - Witt, Dorothy, 1986 (Box 20)
  - Wolk, Michael, 1984-1988 (Box 20)
  - Wood, Peter, 1980 (Box 20)
  - Wortis, Avi, 1984 (Box 20)
  - Wreszin, Michael, 1986 (Box 20)
  - Wright, Daphne, 1988-1990 (Box 20)
  - Wright, John, 1981 (Box 20)
  - Wright, L. R. (Bunny), 1983-1996, 2001-2003, 9 folders (Box 20)
  - Wyler, Susan, 1979-1988 (Box 20)
  - Young, Jeffrey, 1991-1994, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Zevin, Dan, 1993-1994 (Box 20)
  - Zhang Jie, 1986-1988 (Box 20)
  - Non-clients, 1986-1991 (Box 20)
  - Non-clients, 1990-1992, 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Non-clients, 1991-1993 (Box 20)
  - Non-clients, 1992 (Box 20)
  - Non-clients, 1993, 2 folders (Box 20)
  - Non-clients, 1994 (Box 20)
  - Non-clients, 1995 (Box 20)
  - Editors, 1987-1989 (Box 20)
- Agent Correspondence, 1979-1994, 2 boxes
  The Agent Correspondence Series documents the VBLA's relationship with partner literary agents and agencies, largely abroad, as they worked to recruit and sell literary contracts. Files include correspondence covering multiple clients, as well as the status of various literary works and contracts with various publishers overseas. Heavily represented is the VBLA's parnership with Lydia Galton's agency, whose files have been arranged by client name. This series also includes the VBLA's materials related to film adaptations of their clients' works.
  - Antonelli, Antonella, 1987-1992 (Box 21)
  - Balcells, Carmen, 1984-1987 (Box 21)
  - Campbell, Maria, 1985-1988 (Box 21)
  - Coleman, Pat, 1984-1987 (Box 21)
  - Coleman, Smith and Claypool, 1984-1985 (Box 21)
  - Creative Artists Agency, 1984 (Box 21)
  - Eady, Toby, 1988-1992 (Box 21)
  - Elfriede, Pexa, 1983-1987 (Box 21)
  - Film correspondence, 1985-1995, 5 folders (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Avery, Martha: 1987-1990 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Barker, A.L., 1987-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Barraclough, June, 1986-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Bielski, Nella, 1986-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Bowling, Harry, 1988-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Chun-Chan Yeh, 1986-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Collange, Christiane, 1985-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Davis, Jennifer, 1986-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Druett, Joan, 1986-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Dunbar, Maureen, 1985-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Duo Duo, 1989-1990 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Frank, Katherine, 1986-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Fyfield, Frances, 1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Gee, Sue, 1989-1990 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Houying, Dai, 1984-1986 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Ingoldby, Grace, 1984-1986 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: LeVernoy, Alec, 1987-1988 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Lewinski, Jorge, 1987 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Marsh, Jan, 1986-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Mason, Anita, 1990 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Mayle, Peter, 1993 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Montero, Gloria, 1990 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Pan, Lynn, 1985-1990 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Sebag-Montefiore, Hugh, 1990 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Zhang Xianliang, 1988-1989 (Box 21)
  - Galton, Lydia: Wright, Daphne, 1989-1990 (Box 21)
  - Irving, Janet Turnbull, 1992-1993 (Box 21)
  - Japan UNI, 1983-1988 (Box 21)
  - Kavanagh, Jennifer, 1988-1995, 4 folders (Box 21)
  - Lapautre, Michelle, 1983-1989 (Box 21)
  - Liepman Agency, 1984-1989 (Box 21)
  - McInerney Associates, 1987-1988 (Box 21)
  - Sane, Lennert, 1979-1992 (Box 22)
  - Siegel, Rosalie, 1988 (Box 22)
  - Stein, Abner, 1981-1994, 4 folders (Box 22)
- Professional Organizations, 1975-1995, 1 box
  This series contains Virginia Barber's personal files from her work with various literary organizations, including the Association of Authors' Representatives, the Independent Literary Agents Association, and the Women's Media Group.
  - Association of Authors' Representatives, general, 1991-1992 (Box 22)
  - Association of Authors' Representatives, Board minutes, 1992-1993 (Box 22)
  - Association of Authors' Representatives Board, 1993 (Box 22)
  - Association of Authors' Representatives, general, 1994 (Box 22)
  - Association of Authors' Representatives Board, 1994 (Box 22)
  - Association of Authors' Representatives, meeting, 1995 (Box 22)
  - Association of Authors' Representatives, insurance, 1995 (Box 22)
  - Canada Book Week: Adams, Paul, 1985 (Box 22)
  - Drew University Board of Visitors, 1993-1995 (Box 22)
  - Frankfurt Book Fair, 1989 (Box 22)
  - Independent Literary Agents Association, 1975-1990, 5 folders (Box 22)
  - Women's Media Group, 1978-1981 (Box 22)